<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  
    <title type="text" xml:lang="en">Ronak Sakhuja</title>
    <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://ronaksakhuja.github.io/atom.xml"/>
  
  <link href="http://ronaksakhuja.github.io/"/>
  <id>http://ronaksakhuja.github.io/</id>
  <updated>2022-06-11T11:26:15Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Ronak Sakhuja</name>
    <email>ronaksakhuja@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <rights type="text">Copyright © 2022 Ronak Sakhuja. All rights reserved.</rights>
  
  <entry>
  <title type="text">Project - DTU Farewell 2020</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ronaksakhuja.github.io/post1.html" />
  <id>http://ronaksakhuja.github.io/post1</id>
  <published>2020-05-29T00:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2020-05-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <h1 id="heading1">DTU Farewell 2020</h1>

<p>I graduated from Delhi Technological University in 2020. If you still remember, that was the first year of the Covid-19 Pandemic. There was a lockdown all over the world, and things in New Delhi were not going any better. In normal times, we have a farewell party in our university consisting of Dance, music and everyone writing short farewell messages on each other's tshirts. These messages are called scribbles.</p>
<p>
With everything going Online, and our colleges being shut down, I along with my friends decided to make a website and try to replicate what we do in an offline farewell. We created a social media website for our farewell in a few days, built on <b>PHP Codeigniter framework and Mysql database</b> and launched it to our batch of more than 2000 students.
</p>
<h2>Features</h2>
<ol>

  <li> Scribble Wall
  Each user has their own profiles on which other users can post their scribbles. Each scribble has a like functionality as well.
  <li>DTU Photowall</li>
  A common place for everyone to upload their memories of college. Everyone can see those and miss the beautiful 4 years they spent in the university.
  <li>2 Truths and 1 Lie</li>
  A game where every user puts in three statements on their profiles, and others come and vote to find which one of them is a lie
  <li>Give a Title</li>
  People can give other users a title, and everyone can like titles posted by others. It can be some funny memory associated with them.
  <li>Profile page</li>
  Each user can set their yearbook quote, display photo and their batch

&lt;/ol&gt;
  

<hr />
<h2>Tech Stack</h2>
Backend is built on <b>PHP Codeigniter with Mysql database</b>.<br />
Website was hosted on <b>Microsoft Azure Virtual Machine</b>, SSL provided by <b>letsencrypt</b>.<br />
Implemented <b>OAuth2</b> using Google Login APIs.

<hr />

  <h2>Code</h2>
The code is closed source at the moment. We plan to host this as a paid service in future for universities. Do get in touch with me to learn about any implementation we did in detail.

<h2 id="media">Video Demo</h2>
 
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H9KZO6ec8mU" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>


  
</li></ol>
 ]]></content>
</entry>



</feed>
